<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Andre Lin | My Simple Site]]></title><description><![CDATA[Computer Science & Mathematics undergraduate. If you're looking to bridge the gap between software development and ML deployment, I could be the person you're looking for.]]></description><link>https://4ndrelim.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 21:34:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Embark On A New Chapter With A Ton Of Unearned Confidence]]></title><description><![CDATA[A New Semester Again, it’s 3am into the night. I should really be clearing some backlog but we don’t always make the best decisions, so…]]></description><link>https://4ndrelim.github.io/blog/another-busy-semester/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://4ndrelim.github.io/blog/another-busy-semester/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 03:23:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;A New Semester&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, it’s 3am into the night. I should really be clearing some backlog but we don’t always make the best decisions, so September’s piece came early. Not a bad idea actually, I can foresee September is going to be a really, really busy month. It’s peak period for interviews and technical assessments, school work will start ramping up, and perhaps most problematic of all, my reluctance to give up on playtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Academia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret among those who know me that I am a bit of a nerd (maybe more than a bit..). I like learning new concepts and explore different ideas, in Computer Science and Math, even though i’m not a particularly fast learner. But that doesn’t deter me from yet again taking a full coursework of math and cs modules while trying to pull my CAP (GPA equivalent) up. &lt;em&gt;Talk about shooting oneself in the foot lol&lt;/em&gt;. Still, it doesn’t end there. During summer, I embarked on two research projects on Machine Learning to further improve myself. Things have gotten much more interesting in recent weeks and i’ve decided to continue my efforts in these areas throughout the semester, hopeful it culminates into well-received publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wait.. There’s More?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with the schedule lies in the planner. Sure, I like to study but boy do I like my playtime as well. You might be wondering what I meant by playtime, don’t worry it’s nothing philandering, I just meant time spent climbing and hanging out with friends from both clubs and outside of clubs. I’m part of both Climbing and Mountaineering club, so I spend my nights either climbing or running up and down hills. Naturally, I wouldn’t be going for every session, but i’m typically in-charge for wall related matters and since both clubs are home to climbers, it’s 2-birds-with-1-stone. What i’ve realised is that I really enjoy spending time and interacting with people during these leisure climbs. Some are extremely passionate climbers looking to further challenge themselves, some are beginners with their new-found love for climbing, and others who still climb, but mostly drop by for a chit-chat session. &lt;em&gt;It’s a good vibe&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It’s Not All Play!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Climbing has garnered much attention in recent years and its evident that there is a strong demand for it in school as well. Climbing club never has to worry about a lack of registration. But an issue remains - there’s no avenue for outdoor climbs. In Singapore, we mostly climb indoors (Dairy farm.. T_T) but at some point in a climber’s journey, his itchy hands and wandering mind will direct him to the natural world. Most outdoor climbing trips are exclusively hosted for a select group of friends, and rightfully so. The barrier to entry is rather high, and you wouldn’t want to start climbing outdoors by yourself with no experience whatsoever. Even for those who are experienced in indoor climbing, outdoor climbing is an altogether different beast. The risk is high but can be mitigated if assisted by the right hands. That said, no experienced climbers would want to travel out of Singapore just to be a ‘belay slave’ (a term used to describe climbers who often end up tending to beginners and having to belay them rather than being able to focus on their own climbs). Hence, the outdoor climbing scene hasn’t grown much even though the demand is high.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So that’s where I step in!&lt;/strong&gt; A friend of mine from Mountaineering Club is really passionate about climbing. He’s one of the more ‘friendly’ climbers around, not just solely interested in his own self-progression, but also seeking to spread the love of climbing to the rest of the NUS community. Specifically, he wishes to make outdoor climbing accessible to many more, even for beginners who seek the thrill of the sport. A commendable objective! And that’s where I realised too, that I am in the perfect position to share and execute his vision! My involvement in both the school’s Climbing and Mountaineering clubs might help to bring any talks of collaboration to fruition. So we sprung into action. Now, we are deep in the midst of planning our very first pilot trial of bringing climbers to Batu Caves in Malaysia, as early as September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I Shall Look Back One Day And Hopefully Smile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exciting? &lt;em&gt;Definitely&lt;/em&gt;. Ambitious? &lt;em&gt;Indeed&lt;/em&gt;. Audacious? &lt;em&gt;Perhaps&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Romanticsm tells us that in order to make the most of our human potential, we must have as many different experiences as we can.&lt;/em&gt; I’m quite the pragmatist, but in this regard, i’m every bit a &lt;strong&gt;romanticist&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, these are what will keep me really busy this semester. To cope with my heavy involvement in school and club activities, i’ve finally (after 2 years of staying off-campus) decided it would be best to make NUS my home of the 3 next months. Hopefully my trusty Mac alongside the life-saving monitor, handy chalkbag, and smelly harness will tide me through the storms to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 590px; margin: 0 0 30px;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/16cf3653fb3226b738add6b7bd87bcee/eea4a/humble_abode.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwAAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMFAv/EABUBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEC/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAFbF5iqZMB//8QAGhABAAIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIDABESIf/aAAgBAQABBQIu9bdvZkqAYnMCO8//xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQ/9oACAEDAQE/AT//xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQ/9oACAECAQE/AT//xAAbEAADAAIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIhMREiUf/aAAgBAQAGPwLvdCcvBsU5b9NHJ//EABsQAQACAgMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAETFRQXGB/9oACAEBAAE/IUwAdRUTacCD2W9aXoRcWrS45wJ//9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABCr7//EABcRAQADAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEWH/2gAIAQMBAT8QyVP/xAAXEQADAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREx/9oACAECAQE/EK9RT//EAB0QAQADAAIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAEAESExQWFxgaH/2gAIAQEAAT8QJ3Ix14QOIPkUy5Q7ZElRHIiOS5lgD18g1O0+iP79iAUrgF3P/9k=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;room&quot;
        title=&quot;room&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/16cf3653fb3226b738add6b7bd87bcee/1c72d/humble_abode.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/16cf3653fb3226b738add6b7bd87bcee/a80bd/humble_abode.jpg 148w,
/static/16cf3653fb3226b738add6b7bd87bcee/1c91a/humble_abode.jpg 295w,
/static/16cf3653fb3226b738add6b7bd87bcee/1c72d/humble_abode.jpg 590w,
/static/16cf3653fb3226b738add6b7bd87bcee/a8a14/humble_abode.jpg 885w,
/static/16cf3653fb3226b738add6b7bd87bcee/fbd2c/humble_abode.jpg 1180w,
/static/16cf3653fb3226b738add6b7bd87bcee/eea4a/humble_abode.jpg 1280w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;P.S. Title was inspired by a quote by Michael from The Good Place. It was enjoyable and was one of the few series I stuck with till the end. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The First Commit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Originality..? So, i’ve finally come around to making my own site. Frankly, ‘making’ is giving me too much credit.. I didn’t have to do much…]]></description><link>https://4ndrelim.github.io/blog/the-first-commit/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://4ndrelim.github.io/blog/the-first-commit/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 05:23:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Originality..?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, i’ve finally come around to making my own site. Frankly, ‘making’ is giving me too much credit.. I didn’t have to do much aside from customizing certain sections. Even the selection of the theme is inspired by a senior with a similar site. That said, I do like the simplicity of the design and the features it offers. I think it suits me. After all, front-end really isn’t my forte and I doubt i’d make a good UI/UX designer. Anyway, the default site also comes with a blog. I pondered for awhile whether to have it removed but figured it isn’t such a bad idea to leave it as a dumping ground for my thoughts every now and then. So, here I am :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;And So The Hustle Continues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t yet mentioned what even spurred this on. But you might’ve guessed it. August is the time when most (big) firms begin their recruitment process. Every computing kid down the block is scrambling to beef up their resumes, color their portfolios and impress with dynamic sites. &lt;em&gt;Scary&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out, i’m no exception. It’s difficult not to feel the pressure when everyone around you is spending most of their waking hours in preparation while juggling a full term of coursework. I even bailed from an exciting diving and hiking trip at Dragon Horns at Tioman Island (Malaysia) with my fellow mountaineering friends :’( . I was the only one (save the exchanger) not to go, so yeah FOMO was strong. Still, I’m glad they are having a blast. It’s unfortunate how much of a rat race this has become but let’s leave that discussion to some other time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 590px; margin: 0 0 30px;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/0bc9a4b4436fc5bb3aad9704611f84cf/eea4a/lovely_friends.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 56.08108108108109%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAALABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGAAAAwEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMEAQX/xAAWAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACAAH/2gAMAwEAAhADEAAAAXKn3LokoV//xAAZEAACAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAgADERD/2gAIAQEAAQUCcIApraCpMuYngds//8QAFhEAAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAER/9oACAEDAQE/AUoQ/8QAFREBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARD/2gAIAQIBAT8BZ//EABoQAQEAAgMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAECEiMTL/2gAIAQEABj8C8lojgYG7v//EAB0QAQABBQADAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAESExQVFhocH/2gAIAQEAAT8hRtw9zDPiJbKchDV5AKbrfJuE/9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABAsL//EABYRAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARMf/aAAgBAwEBPxDMp//EABYRAAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEf/aAAgBAgEBPxB6VH//xAAdEAEAAgICAwAAAAAAAAAAAAABACERMUHRUWGh/9oACAEBAAE/EAlwxiukQSwOiWDXyMDICwEZSmvc2sZWF89mYY1KE//Z&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;friends&quot;
        title=&quot;friends&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/0bc9a4b4436fc5bb3aad9704611f84cf/1c72d/lovely_friends.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/0bc9a4b4436fc5bb3aad9704611f84cf/a80bd/lovely_friends.jpg 148w,
/static/0bc9a4b4436fc5bb3aad9704611f84cf/1c91a/lovely_friends.jpg 295w,
/static/0bc9a4b4436fc5bb3aad9704611f84cf/1c72d/lovely_friends.jpg 590w,
/static/0bc9a4b4436fc5bb3aad9704611f84cf/a8a14/lovely_friends.jpg 885w,
/static/0bc9a4b4436fc5bb3aad9704611f84cf/fbd2c/lovely_friends.jpg 1180w,
/static/0bc9a4b4436fc5bb3aad9704611f84cf/eea4a/lovely_friends.jpg 1280w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I was going about my own preparation (mostly LeetCode grind. &lt;strong&gt;Disgusting - yes, I know&lt;/strong&gt;) when someone in my Computing cohort announced that he has compiled a list of firms, mostly top and possibly out-of-my-league ones, and has kindly decided to share with everyone else. Naturally, this is a great thing! And it saves me time having to look up some pesky companies’ careers pages whom tend to avoid LinkedIn or other job searching sites. But I glanced through the profile of interested applicants, a close friend’s one as well, and thought to myself &lt;em&gt;damn.. they’ve got some real solid portfolios and pretty sites&lt;/em&gt;. It made me anxious. I thought about making a site from scratch too, but felt my time could be better spent elsewhere, like writing now LOL. But seriously, I am quite certain I would be distracted midway and wind up reading some paper or whatnot in the name of learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some reservations about how consequential having a (very simple) portfolio site would be. But I suppose it does provide some form of self-assurance, if nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there we have it, 5am deep into the night (or morning wtv), just finished wrapping up the site and left a short read for whoever that chances upon this blog. Goodnight -.-&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>